# **Carissa Shum**

778-387-2836 cwkshum.github.io carissa\_shum@sfu.ca A Vancouver based developer and designer with a goal of creating a positive user experience within every project by combining design with a programming skill set. The aim of exceeding the needs of the intended users inspires the development of meaningful applications ranging from the web to mobile.

#### Design Skills

- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Ideating
- Interface Design

## **Technical Skills**

- HTML / CSS
- JavaScript
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Premiere

- PHP
- MySQL
- Adobe Illustrator
- Android Studio

- C/C++
- Processing
- Adobe After Effects
- Figma

- lava
- Arduino
- Adobe InDesign
- Axure RP

## Web Experience

March - June 2021

# Web Design & Development Internship SeeRem

- Created mockups and a prototype in a team of three using Figma for SeeRem's web application to be used as a reference during its development process.
- Restructured the existing website to better convey the SeeRem application to potential customers and coded the changes using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Successfully launched the SeeRem site using the Google Cloud Platform which resulted in positive recognition from the company's CEO.

Sept - Dec 2020

# Front-end & Back-end Developer (Academic Project)

#### **Shoe Addiction**

- Worked in a team of three to make a fictional shoe store web application, focusing on the back-end handling of user requests to better understand the structure of present-day e-commerce sites.
- Implemented a MySQL database to store account information, retrieve product or user data, and record updates for a fully developed web application.
- Coded the site using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for seamless user interaction, including filtering abilities, and PHP to process database information.

#### **Design Experience**

Jan 2018 - Present

#### Multimedia Designer

#### Panorama School of Dance

- Editing together camp videos to be shared with the families which feature dance performances, highlights, and a photo slideshow using Adobe Premiere.
- Designed display slides for the waiting rooms to inform students and parents about current and upcoming events in 2018 and 2019.
- Compiled images and formatted them to be projected onto the theatre's stage to be used as backdrops for two of the studio's yearly dance productions.





Feb - April 2021

# App Developer & UI/UX Designer (Academic Project)

VanCity Cycling

- Developed an Android cycling route planning app in a team of two in collaboration with CityStudio and the City of Vancouver to promote bike riding as a mode of transportation for novice cyclists.
- Designed the branding as well as the user interface of the application and coded the app's functionality using Java, which resulted in favourable feedback from the teaching team.
- Presented the completed application to the City of Vancouver's Transportation
  Division where the app received recognition for its friendly interface and
  various planning features that would benefit beginner cyclists by making
  biking in the city more convenient.

# Other Experience

Sept 2018 - Present

#### **Dance Teacher**

Panorama School of Dance

- Teaching multiple ballet, jazz, and lyrical classes every week to children ranging from the age of three to eleven years old.
- Choreographing dance routines for the studio's yearly productions that showcases the abilities and talents of each dancer.
- Preparing dancers for the Royal Academy of Dance ballet exams by following the outlined syllabus resulting in students receiving positive exam scores.
- Conducted weekly online dance classes which allowed students to continue dancing safely during the 2020 pandemic.

Sept 2019 - Feb 2020

#### SIAT TechTeams Leader

Simon Fraser University

- Collaborated with three other student leaders to organize weekly sessions for first-year students to help them transition into university and to learn about the Interactive Arts and Technology program.
- Facilitated twelve workshop sessions that encouraged discussion among peers while assisting in the development of their design skills.
- Created presentations and activities that educated students on topics regarding design principles and web design.

#### Education

2018 - Present

# **Simon Fraser University**

BSc. in Interactive Arts and Technology

- Recipient of the Simon Fraser University Undergraduate Scholars Entrance Scholarship (with distinction)
- President's Honour Roll (2019-2021)
- Dean's Honour Roll (2019-2021)